car.org 2019-04-08

# Privacy Policies

**  Privacy Policy for C.A.R. Online (**[ **www.car.org**](http://www.car.org/) **)**

**Effective June 5, 2006  
**  
The CALIFORNIA ASSOCIATION OF REALTORS® ("C.A.R.") has created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy and so that you, as a visitor to C.A.R. Online ("Web site"), will be aware of the uses made of information that may be generated as a result of you using our Web site. 

**What information is generated when you visit C.A.R. Online?**

Depending on how you use our Web site, certain types of personal and nonpersonal information may be generated and collected.  For example, you may give us your name or e-mail address when you complete a registration screen, respond to a questionnaire or submit an e-mail to us.  Any personal information that you provide to us will be used by us primarily to fulfill the stated objective for which the information was requested or collected (e.g. if information is provided as a result of you e-mailing us, we will use the information provided, such as e-mail address, to respond to you). 

Other types of information that may be generated and collected when you use our Web site is information that we consider nonpersonal in nature.  For example, we may collect the name of the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, aol.com, if you are connecting from an America Online account); the date and time you access our site or and the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to our site.  We use this information to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our Web site and to help us make our Web site more useful to visitors. 

**Use of Cookies**

What is a cookie?  A cookie is a data file that is created and stored on your computer's hard drive when you visit a Web site.  The typical purposes of a cookie is to make your use of the Web site easier and more convenient and to assist the Web site in tracking your use of the site.  For example, a cookie may save the registration information, passwords, purchases or preferences that you create when using a Web site so you don't have to reenter this information.  Cookies may also tell the Web site which areas of the site are popular and which aren't.  Cookie technology is used by most major Web sites and is considered an industry standard for the Internet. 

Our Web site uses cookie technology to verify user information.  (Please see the section titled 'Advertisements' for more information concerning advertisers.).  Also, most Internet browsers are initially set to accept cookies.  If you prefer, you may set your browser so that it refuses cookies or alerts you when cookies are being created on your hard drive.  You should be aware though that by not accepting cookies, you may impair your ability to use certain shopping or password protected areas of web sites. 

**REALTOR® Directory**

C.A.R. is a private trade association consisting of real estate professionals.   As one of the many benefits of membership with C.A.R., we make available on our Web site a searchable database of our members called the "REALTOR® Directory."  The directory can be used by the public to locate and contact our members by such characteristics as name, company or city location. 

_The member information made available through the REALTOR® Directory is intended to contain only the business information of our members.    Under no circumstances will we intentionally display or make available on our Web site the personal home addresses or phone numbers of our members. _

If you are a member of C.A.R. and would like to be removed from the REALTOR® Directory, please see the section called "Choice/Opt Out."  If you have corrections or updates to the Directory, please see the section called "Corrections/Updates." 

**Directors and Committee Members**

For use by the members of C.A.R., we make available on the Web site the names of members who are serving as directors or committee members of C.A.R. 

**"Contact Us" Feature**

Like most sites on the Internet, our Web site contains a feature that allows you to contact us with your comments or questions.   Not surprisingly, we call this feature "Contact Us."  To use this feature, there is an icon at the top of each page on our Web site which you can click onto.  When you do click this icon, a screen will prompt you to provide us with certain information, such as your first and last name, email address, phone and fax number and your address, including your city and state. 

The information collected through the "Contact Us" feature is used to investigate and respond to your inquiries.  If you are a member, we may also use the information you provide to update our membership records. 

**C.A.R. Online Product Mall**

The C.A.R. Online Product Mall is an area on our Web site where you can purchase various real estate related products.   In order to process and complete your orders though the Mall, we will need to ask you for certain information, such as your name, company name, address, state and zip code.  We also need to ask you for your credit card number and expiration date. 

The information collected through the C.A.R. Online Product Mall is used to process your order and may also be used to keep track of the amount and types of purchases being made through the C.A.R. Online Product Mall.  We may also use your email address or mailing address to send you information regarding updates to the products you purchased or new products which may be of interest to you.  When you click on the Product Mall icon, you may be taken to another Web site where you may purchase products, and if so, you agree to be taken to and bound by the terms of that Web site?s privacy policy. 

With respect to your credit card information, this information is sent encrypted to a secure server.  The information is then used to complete your purchase order.  Please see the section called "Security" for more information about the security of our Web site. 

**Links to Other Sites**

In many areas of our Web site, we have included links to other Internet sites which we feel add to or improve the quality of our Web site.   While we hope you find these links helpful, we cannot assume responsibility for the privacy practices or the content of any linked site.  Therefore, we encourage you to investigate and determine the privacy policy and practices of any linked site prior to providing information to the linked site. 

**Consumer Newsletter Service**

We currently offer as a free service to our members a "Consumer Newsletter Service."  Through this service, our members can send a customized electronic newsletter to clients and customers, which includes pertinent real estate related information as well as a photo of the member and his or her business contact information.  To provide this service, we have retained Inman News Features to provide the content and technical support. 

To sign up for the Customer Newsletter Service, we ask you to provide certain information, such as your name, phone number, business postal and email addresses and your web site address (if you have one).   In addition, you can submit the names and email address of your clients and customers which you want to be subscribers of the service. 

_Under no circumstances will the information provided you when signing up for the Customer Newsletter Service, including the names and email address of clients and customers, be used for any purpose other than to perform the Customer Newsletter Service_. 

**Surveys**

We may from time to time create and use surveys on our Web site.  Most surveys are simple ?click box? surveys where you click a box on the screen to indicate your response.  However, we may from time to time ask you for your name, email address or demographic information.  If a survey does ask you this information, we will use the information to complete the survey, compile statistics and update member records. 

**Contests**

We may from time to time run contests on our Web site.  If our contests require you to provide personal or demographic information, we will use this information primarily to complete the contest and update member records. 

**Advertisements**

Like many other sites on the Internet, we sell advertising space on our Web site to other companies.  The advertising space we sell is usually in the form of an electronic "advertisement banner."  An advertisement banner is essentially a graphic link to the actual Internet site of the advertiser. 

While we hope you find our advertiser's products helpful, we cannot assume any responsibility for the privacy practices of our advertisers.  Therefore, like any other Internet site you may visit, we encourage you to become knowledgeable of the privacy policies and practices of our advertisers prior to providing information on their sites. 

**Public Chat Rooms or Forums**

From time to time a discussion forum, bulletin board, blog, chat area, news group, community, or other feature designed so that Users may upload data and images or communicate with others ("Forum") may be made available to Users on this Site. C.A.R., in its sole discretion, reserves the right to review, control or edit any text, data, images, files, or other materials that may be uploaded, posted or submitted in any Forum ("Submissions") as well as the right to refuse to post any such Submission.  All Submissions are subject to the Terms of Use.  Please remember that any information you disclose on these types of features will be accessible to the public and you should exercise caution prior to disclosing any personal information on these features.

 **C.A.R. Toolbar**

C.A.R. will not collect any information from you that could identify you personally when you download, install, and use the C.A.R. Toolbar. The C.A.R. Toolbar will not track your searches or browsing habits, and it will not install any other software programs on your computer without your consent.  We will not gather information from the C.A.R. Toolbar to send any marketing or promotional materials to you, or to communicate with you by phone, fax or e-mail without your consent.  C.A.R. may collect non-personal information concerning how many times the C.A.R. Toolbar download link was accessed and how many times the C.A.R. Toolbar was downloaded for internal business and statistical purposes. 

**Required by Law**

We may disclose information provided by you if we are legally required to do so, such as by court order or subpoena. 

**Security**

We have adopted what we consider to be reasonable security measures to protect against the loss, theft, misuse and alteration of information collected through our Web site.  However, if you are concerned about the security of the Internet or our Web site, we suggest that you not provide this information. 

**Other Products and Services**

Although we generally collect and use information to fulfill the stated objective for which the information was requested or collected, we may also provide the information to our subsidiaries so that they may send you information regarding other products or services that may be valuable or interesting to you. 

**Children's Guidelines**

Our Web site does not currently attempt to collect or solicit information from persons who are under the age of eighteen.  However, given the anonymous nature of the Internet, it is possible that someone under the age of eighteen may access our Web site and provide us with personal information.  If this situation occurs and it is brought to our attention, we will not use the information in any way without prior parental consent and we will take all reasonable steps to prevent it from occurring again. 

**Choice/Opt-Out**

Our Web site provides you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us.  Also, if you are a member of C.A.R., you can choose to opt out of having your name included in the REALTOR® Directory.  To exercise your opt-out privilege, please feel free to e-mail us at _[contactus@car.org](mailto:contactus@car.org)_  or write us at 525 South Virgil Avenue, Los Angeles, CA   90020, Attn: C.A.R. Online Web Developer.  Please be advised that if you are a member and choose to opt-out of receiving communications from the Web site, this may affect your ability to receive other e-mail communications that are sent to members of C.A.R. 

**Corrections/Updates**

If you are a member and there is information about you on our Web site which needs to be corrected or updated, please feel free to email us at _[contactus@car.org](mailto:contactus@car.org)_  or write us at 525 South Virgil Avenue, Los Angeles, CA  90020, Attn: C.A.R. Online Web Developer.  However, in order for the correction or update to be permanent, you will need to contact your local association and make sure that the correction or update is made in their records as well. 

**Contacting our Web site**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of our Web site, or your dealings with our Web site, please feel free to email us at _[contactus@car.org](mailto:contactus@car.org)_  or write us at 525 South Virgil Avenue, Los Angeles, CA  90020, Attn: C.A.R. Online Web Developer. 

**Changes to Privacy Policy Statement**

With the ever-changing environment of the Internet and to maintain our ability to improve the quality and safety of our Web site, we reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time.  In the event we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy, we will notify you by updating the Policy's Effective Date and indicating the previous effective date.  As you use our Web site, we encourage you to periodically check back with this Privacy Policy for changes that we may make.  Your continued use of our Web site will constitute your agreement to any changes we make and if you do not agree with a change, please refrain from using our Web site.  Thank you! ****

**The   CALIFORNIA ASSOCIATION OF  REALTORS®** **  
Member Information Privacy Policy**

The CALIFORNIA ASSOCIATION OF REALTORS® ("C.A.R.") has created this Member Information Privacy Policy to demonstrate its firm commitment to the privacy of member information and so that you, as a member of C.A.R., will be aware of the uses made of your member information by C.A.R. 

1.  Confidential.  In general, all member information provided to C.A.R. by its members is treated as confidential and C.A.R. uses its best efforts to keep such information confidential and prevent unauthorized use. 

2.  C.A.R. Member Communications.  From time to time, C.A.R. will use your preferred contact information to send you regular and special membership communications and publications.  For example, members of C.A.R. receive a monthly membership magazine and we will need to access and use your preferred mailing address to send you this publication.  ?Preferred contact information? as used in this section and the remainder of this privacy policy is the information pertaining to your name, email address, mailing address, telephone and facsimile numbers which you indicated to your local association of REALTORS® as the preferred contact information to receive communications.  For example, you may have indicated your business address as your preferred mailing address and your home telephone number as your preferred telephone number. 

3.  Member Requests.  From time to time, you may contact C.A.R. and make requests.  In order to respond to your request, we may need to access and use your member information.  For example, we may need to access your preferred mailing address to send you the information you requested. 

4.  REALTOR® Directory.  As one of the many benefits of membership with C.A.R., we make available on our web site ([www.car.org](http://www.car.org/)) a searchable database of our members called the "REALTOR® Directory."  The purpose of this directory is to assist the public in locating and contacting our members.  The Directory contains searchable characteristics about our members, such as the member?s name, company or city location.  The member information made available through the REALTOR® Directory is intended to contain only the business information of our members.  Under no circumstances will we intentionally display or make available your personal home addresses or telephone number in the REALTOR® Directory unless you indicated these to your local association of REALTORS® as your preferred contact information.  If you would like to be removed from the REALTOR® Directory, please see the section of this privacy policy called "Choice/Opt Out."  If you have corrections or updates to the directory, please see the section called "Corrections/Updates." 

5.  Names of Directors and Committee Members; Use of Preferred Contact Information.  For use by C.A.R. members and for purposes of conducting C.A.R. Board of Directors meetings, we make available on our web site (www.car.org) and in other print and electronic formats the names of those C.A.R. members serving as directors or committee members of C.A.R.  In addition, in order to provide meeting related information and to send official Board of Directors notices, we access and use the preferred contact information of C.A.R. directors and committee members, including email and mailing addresses. 

6.  Third Parties.  From time to time, C.A.R. makes your preferred contact information available to Member Advantage Program affinity partners and approved strategic business partners to enable them to notify you about products and services that C.A.R. feels you may be interested in.  C.A.R. may also make your preferred contact information available to third parties who do work on behalf of C.A.R. Under no circumstances will we intentionally make available your personal home addresses or telephone number to third parties unless you indicated these as your preferred contact information.  If you do not want your preferred contact information to be provided to third parties, please see the section of this privacy policy called "Choice/Opt Out." 

7.  Request from the Public.  If the public contacts C.A.R. and requests information regarding one of its members, we may check our member database and verify to the public whether the person(s) is in fact a member of C.A.R.  We may also provide the public with the name and telephone number of the firm that the member is affiliated with and the local association through which the member holds membership.  However, in no event will we provide personal information to the public, such as your home address and telephone number, unless required by a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process or in the case of imminent physical harm to the public or other members. 

8.  ?Listservs.?  From time to time, C.A.R. may create and maintain a ?listserv? for a particular topic or subject of interest to its members.  A listserv is a program that sends emails to the addresses on the listserv?s list.  If you provided your email address to C.A.R., your email address may be used on a listserv.  In other situations, the listserv may only be available if you affirmatively sign up to participate.  In any event, if you decide you do not want to participate in a particular listserv, the first email you receive from the listserv should provide you instructions on how to opt out of the service. 

9.  Orders; Credit Card Information.  C.A.R. sells various real estate related products and services to its members.  In order to process and complete orders, we may need to access your member information, such as your name, company name, address, state and zip code.  This information will only be used to process your order (i.e. ship and mail your order) and to send you information regarding updates to the products or services you purchased.  If you pay for your order by credit card, we will need to ask you for your credit card number and expiration date, which will be used solely to complete your order and otherwise kept confidential. 

10.  Choice/Opt Out.  C.A.R. recognizes the importance of your privacy.  If you do not want your member information displayed or used in one or more of the manners described above, please read the following instructions: 

To opt out of having your name and business contact information included in the REALTOR® Directory, please email us at: [contactus@car.org](mailto:contactus@car.org) or write us at: 525 South Virgil Avenue, Los Angeles, CA 90020, Attn: C.A.R. Online Web Developer.  Please be sure to specify in your email or writing that you want to be removed from the REALTOR® Directory on C.A.R. Online.  To insure your request is processed timely and accurately, please provide the following information with your request: first name, last name, office name, office telephone number, DRE license number, and NRDS or C.A.R. member number.  C.A.R. will process your request as quickly as possible; however, your name may continue to be reproduced in the REALTOR® Directory until the request is ultimately processed.  C.A.R. apologizes in advance for any inconveniences this may cause. 

To opt out of having your preferred contact information provided to third parties, please email us at: [contactus@car.org](mailto:contactus@car.org) or write us at: 525 South Virgil Avenue, Los Angeles, CA 90020, Attn: Third Party Opt Out Request.  To insure your request is processed timely and accurately, please provide the following information with your request: first name, last name, office name, office telephone number, DRE license number, and NRDS or C.A.R. member number.  C.A.R. will process your request as quickly as possible; however, you may continue to receive third party communications until the request is ultimately processed.  C.A.R. apologizes in advance for any inconveniences this may cause. 

Please note, if you are a director or committee member of C.A.R., you cannot opt out of having your name reproduced and your preferred contact information used in the manner described in Sections 4 and 5 above. 

12.  Corrections/Updates.  If there is member information about you which needs to be corrected or updated, please email us at [contactus@car.org](mailto:contactus@car.org) or write us at 525 South Virgil Avenue, Los Angeles, CA 90020, Attn: Membership Records.  However, in order for the correction or update to be permanent, you will need to contact your local association and make sure that the correction or update is made in its records as well. 

13.   Contacting C.A.R.  If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at _[contactus@car.org](mailto:contactus@car.org)_  or write us at 525 South Virgil Avenue, Los Angeles, CA 90020, Attn: C.A.R. Privacy Policy. 

14.  Changes in This Policy.  From time to time, C.A.R. may need to change this privacy policy to better meet the needs of its members.  As such, we reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time.  Such changes may be made without prior notice so we encourage you to periodically check this privacy policy statement for changes that we may make.  Changes to this policy will be effective when posted on C.A.R.'s web site unless determined otherwise by the C.A.R. Board of Directors.
